<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emacs Jedi</title>
    <link>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Emacs Jedi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2012 - 2019, Manish Marahatta; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://manishmarahatta.com.np/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mujo (無常)</title>
      <link>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/post/mujo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/post/mujo/</guid>
      <description>Mujō (無常) means ‘impermanence’ in Japanese. Mujō is the same as anicca(अनिच्चा/अनित्य), the word for ‘impermanence’ in Pāli. Everything within our life is constantly changing and we can be certain that nothing is permanent. Letting go of attachments can bring some level of continuous flow within our life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are Lucky - Dedicated to the one I love</title>
      <link>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/post/you-are-lucky/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/post/you-are-lucky/</guid>
      <description>It has been almost two years since the original writer of this blog post passed away. I haven&amp;rsquo;t met anyone that&amp;rsquo;s remotely more genuine than him. Return if Possible Mohit.
When life put me down in tough situation, I never said &amp;lsquo;Why me?&amp;rsquo; I just said &amp;lsquo;Try me&amp;rsquo;. - Mohit
It is 12:44 in the morning and I don’t feel like sleeping. There were those time in my life where I felt really low and I felt like I had nothing left in me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year in a Review - 2017</title>
      <link>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/post/year-in-a-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/post/year-in-a-review/</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow is January 1st, 2018. I sit here today, on New Years Eve, in a state of reflection as I look back on the past 365 days. I am thinking about how fast and slow this year has gone. About how much has changed.
I’ll start with my last, but most important reason, and that is to sincerely give a big thank you. A thank you to my family, my love, my friends (new + old), my mentors, classmates, coworkers, enemies, and everyone who stood before, with, and against me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Freedom Day 2016</title>
      <link>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/post/sfd-nepal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/post/sfd-nepal/</guid>
      <description>Software Freedom Day 2016, Kathmandu by FOSS Nepal Community (Lead by Mr. Manish Marahatta) was a huge success with more than 10 open communities involved which includes Google Business Group (GBG Kathmandu), Open Knowledge Nepal, Wikipedia, HackProject.org, Kathmandu Living Labs, WliT, Kathmandu University Open Source Club (KUOSC) and many others. With about 500 running and staying participants, this year was one of the biggest celebration of all time. Basically, the event was categorized in three different sections: Keynote and Paper Presentations (Agrawal Hall), Discussion Fora (Stall of different communities) and Hackathon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why your ecommerce startup will fail in Nepal</title>
      <link>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/post/ecommerce-nepal-bad-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/post/ecommerce-nepal-bad-idea/</guid>
      <description>Everyone back in Nepal want to grab the lucarative ecommerce business which seems to be doing well in India along with other part of Asia but thing here in Nepal is quite different. Beforing going big with ecommerce business you should know the business ecosystem of Nepal along with the user behaviour and tech penetration. Most e-commerce websites/startups based in Nepal fail due to the various reasons. Let’s check out some reason which can push your e-commerce into the dead-pool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Torrent Downloader</title>
      <link>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/project/automatic-torrent-downloader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/project/automatic-torrent-downloader/</guid>
      <description>Automatic Torrent Downloader downloads all the torrent files from the internet when the new torrent subject is released.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance of backend web development</title>
      <link>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/post/importance-of-backend-web-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/post/importance-of-backend-web-development/</guid>
      <description>While creating a new website, developers have to focus on both frontend and backend development. The frontend of an application refers to the code that is visible to the website visitors. Normally, frontend code creates interfaces through which the application interacts with the users. On the other hand, the backend code interacts with the server, and delivers content or data to be displayed to the users. So the backend code deals with the application as well as the web server and database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swashank Redemption Analysis</title>
      <link>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/post/swashank-redemption-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/post/swashank-redemption-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Hey I loved Swashank Redemption I really don&amp;rsquo;t care if u didn&amp;rsquo;t. I have done some analysis with my perspective.
Red Red is the lifeline of the prison, the man who can smuggle almost anything into Shawshank from the outside world. By making himself indispensable to the other inmates, Red affords himself protection and an esteemed place in the pecking order of the prison yard. He forces the other men to do business on his terms and knows full well the need to defend his own interests in a world where violence and exploitation are the norm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSS KAA KURA(Philosophy of FOSS)</title>
      <link>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/presentation/foss-kaa-kura/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/presentation/foss-kaa-kura/</guid>
      <description>Today, we FOSS Nepal and Mozilla Nepal organized a Pre SFD event at National School of Sciences (NSS). Pre SFD event is a part of Software Freedom Day (SFD) which is being organized on September 17 at Kathmandu and many other cities in the world. The motive of the Pre SFD event is to inform campus/college students about the SFD as well as providing awareness about open source technologies.
There were two groups of students each with about 40 students in the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart City the Open Way</title>
      <link>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/presentation/smart-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manishmarahatta.com.np/presentation/smart-city/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>